Contact

+541121698420 (Home) ringlord45@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/diegoramirez (LinkedIn)

www.diegoram.me (Personal)

Top Skills

Java

Python

MySQL

Languages

Inglés (Full Professional)

Certifications

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Functional Program Design in Scala

Diego Ramirez

Operations and Co-Founder en Grandridge Labs

Summary

All along my profesional experience I got involved on Software development. Either as developer, architect, consultant, team leader or manager.

I've been working on SD for the last 20 years and every day I find something to learn and improve.

Skills: Development, Software Arquitecture, Oriented Object Analisys and Design, Functional Programming, Java, Python, Scala, PlayFramework, Node.js

Experience

Grandridge Labs
Operations and Co-Founder
January 2018 - Present
Austin y alrededores, Texas, Estados Unidos

Grandridge Labs is a consultancy company which provides out sourcing services. We handle several technologies and approaches to enhance our client business.

Educabot CTO y Co-founder January 2016 - Present Buenos Aires, Argentina

Independent IT Consultant/Contractor Scala Developer January 2017 - Present

whitePrompt
Software Architect
January 2015 - January 2017 (2 years 1 month)

Microservices Design and Implementation, using Scala, Playframework, Akka HTTP and Cassandra.

colegio San Agustin Profesor de Tecnologías de la Información October 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 6 months)

GlobalLogic

Technical Lead / Software Engineer
January 2014 - January 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Service Core implementations, i.e Logging (asynchronous && distributed) and Object && Graph Storage, using Scala y Akka w/ Cassandra, and support to Rabbitmg and OrientDB.

Since all them were microservices, there were built upon Swagger as REST APIs using Jersey, PlayFramework and Spray.io, among others.

Globant

Software Architect November 2012 - January 2014 (1 year 3 months)

At Big Data & High Perfomance Studio.

Diseño e implementacion de servicios REST para portales web y mobile usando Scala y Node.js

FDV Solutions

Software Designer

October 2012 - November 2012 (2 months)

Desarrollo de Aplicacion de MarketPlace para IOS

Socialmetrix

Java Developer

April 2011 - August 2012 (1 year 5 months)

Desarrollo y mantenimiento de aplicaciones Web, Crawling, Web Analytics, Data y Text Mining para Redes Sociales.

Psicofxp S.A.

Planning & Development Manager

October 2008 - April 2011 (2 years 7 months)

Gestion, seguimiento, control y optimizacion de procesos en proyectos para creacion de soluciones informaticas de acceso masivo (Redes sociales).

Implementacion de Metodologias Agiles (Scrum,XP) y Planificacion de Asignacion de Recursos+Flujo de Trabajo.

Analisis e implementacion de innmovaciones tecnologicas.

Diseño y desarrollo de framework propio para persistencia de Objetos y Servicios Multiples. (PHP).

Desarrollo de Sofware para MicroManagment de Produccion con Python (usando Django)

Clarin Global

Developer Senior

August 2008 - October 2008 (3 months)

Analista programador .Net: Desarrollo de Aplicaciones y portales Web.

Desarrollo de componentes para visualizacion de informacion en las Portadas de Cuidad.com y Qmusica.com

Synchro Technologies

Developer

March 2007 - July 2008 (1 year 5 months)

Analista Programador en varios lenguajes (Visual FOX pro, Visual Basic, C#, Java, Php.

- -Modificaciones, mejoras y mantenimientos de los procesos de Facturacion de Edesur (C++ e Informix).
- -Mantinimiento de Sistema de Lectura en Medidores (Java)
- -Desarrollo de interfaces de comunicacion Bancaria para Cepas Argentina.

Merino Aller

Developer

June 2005 - March 2007 (1 year 10 months)

Desarrollo de Producto Enlatado con Visual Fox Pro y Motor de Datos MS SQL. Este es un ERP extenso aplicable a varias industrias con modulos para Comercio Internacional.

Constab

Developer Senior

June 1999 - May 2005 (6 years)

Analista Programador.

Desarrollo de Sistemas a Medida para Sectores Industriales.

Control de Procesos, Costos, Ventas y Expedicion.

Lenguaje Visual Fox Pro con Motor de Datos MSSQL.

Sistema de gestión Administrativa Contable en VB.Net

Aplicativos Contables y de ventas para intranets (C#)

Education

Universidad Abierta Interamericana · (2008)